36 chapter 37 of Black Beauty this LibriVox recording is in the public
domain Black Beauty by Anna Su chapter 37 The Golden
Rule Two or 3 weeks after this, as we came into the yard rather late in the
evening, Polly came running across the road with the lantern (she always brought
it to him if it was not very wet). “It has all come right, Jerry; Mrs
bricks sent her servant this afternoon to ask you to take her out out tomorrow
at 11:00 I said, 'Yes, I thought so, but we supposed she employed someone else now.'”
“'Well,' said he, 'the real fact is, master was put out because Mr. Barker refused to
come on Sundays, and he has been trying other cabs, but there's something wrong
with them all; some drive too fast, and some too slow, and the mistress says
there is not one of them so nice and clean as yours, and nothing will suit her
but Mr. Barker's cab again.'” Polly was almost out of breath, and
Jerry broke out into a merry laugh it will all come right some day or night':
you were right, my dear; you generally are.
Run in and get the supper, and I'll have Jack's harness off and make him snug and
happy in no time.” After this Mrs. Briggs wanted Jerry's cab quite as often as before,
never, however, on a Sunday; but there came a day when we had Sunday work, and this
was how it happened. We had all come home on the Saturday night very tired, and very glad
to think that the next day would be all rest, but so it was not to
be. On Sunday morning Jerry was cleaning me in the yard, when Polly stepped up to
him, looking very full of something. “What is it?” said Jerry. “Well, my
dear,” she said, “poor Diana Brown has just had a letter brought to say that her
mother is dangerously ill, and that she must go directly if she wishes to see
her alive. The place is more than 10 miles miles away from here, out in the
country, and she says if she takes the train she should still have four miles
to walk; and so weak as she is, and the baby only 4 weeks old, of course that
would be impossible; and she wants to know if you would take her in your cab,
and she promises to pay you faithfully, as she can get the
money.” “Tut, tut! we'll see about that. It was not the money I was thinking about,
but of losing our Sunday; the horses are tired, and I am tired, too— —that's what it
pinches.” “It pinches all around for that matter,” said Polly, “for it's only half
Sunday without you, but you know we should do to other people as we should
like they should do to us; and I know very well what I should like if my
mother was dying; and Jerry, dear I'm sure it won't break the Sabbath; for if
pulling a poor beast or donkey out of a pit would not spoil it I'm quite sure
taking poor dinina would not do it.” “Why, Polly, you were as good as the
minister, and so, as I've had my Sunday morning sermon early today you may go
and tell Dina that I'll be ready for her as the clock strikes 10 but stop— —just
step around to butcher bradden's with my compliments, and ask him if he would lend
me his light trap; I know he never uses it on the Sunday, and it would make a
wonderful difference to the horse.” Away she went, and soon returned,
saying that he could have the trap and welcome. “All right,” said he; “now put me up
a bit of bread and cheese, and I'll be back back in the afternoon as soon as I
can.” “And I'll have the meat pie ready for an early tea instead of for dinner,” said
Polly; and away she went, while he made his preparations to the tune of pol's
the woman and no mistake”, of which tune he was very
fond. I was selected and at 10:00 we started, in a light High wheeled gig,
which ran so easily but after the four-wheeled cap it seemed like
nothing. It was a fine May day, and as soon as we were out of the town, the
sweet air, the smell of the fresh grass, and the soft country roads were as
pleasant as they used to be in the old times, and I soon began to feel quite
fresh Diner's family lived in a small farmhouse, up a green lane, close by a
meadow with some fine shady trees; there were two cows feeding in it. A young man
asked Jerry to bring his trap into the meadow, and he would tie me up in the Cow
Shed he wished he had a better stable to offer. “If your cows would not be offended,”
said Cherry there is nothing my horse would like so well as to have an hour or
two in your beautiful meadow; he's quiet, and it would be a rare treat for
him.” “Do, and welcome,” said the young man; “the best we have is at your service for
your kindness to my sister; we should be having some dinner in an hour, and I hope
you'll come in, though with mother so ill we are all out of sorts in the
house Sherry thanked him kindly, but said as he had some dinner with him there was
nothing he should like so well as walking about in the
meadow. When my harness was taken off I did not know what I should do first—
—whether to eat the grass, or roll over on
my back, or lie down and rest, or have a gallop across the meadow out of sheer
spirits at being free; and I did all by turns. Jerry seemed to be quite as happy
as I was; he sat down by a bank under a shady tree, and listened to the birds,
then he sang himself, and read out of the little brown book he is so fond of, then
wandered around the meadow, and down by a little brook, where he picked the flowers
and the Hawthorne and tied them up with long sprays of
ivy; then he gave me a good feed of the oats which he had brought with him; but
the time seemed all too short— —I had not been in a field since I left poor Ginger
at Earl's Hall We came home gently, and Jerry's first words were, as we came into the
yard, “Well, Polly, I have not lost my Sunday after all, for the birds were
singing hymns in every bush, and I joined in the service; and as for Jack, he was
like a young colt.” When he handed Dolly the flowers she jumped about for
joy end of chapter